

Narakorn Butpha

RF Engineer

About

I am an experienced radio planning and optimization with 6 years seeking a job in the field of radio planning and optimization.

- AIS Engineer (Radio Planning and Optimization Engineering)
- Team leader of subcontractor Elabram Systems Co., Ltd

Employment History

RF Engineer at DTAC

August 2021— Present

Project: Telecom work (DTN), Huawei Nokia Ericsson

- Monitor and Optimize OSS KPIs for submit PAC acceptance and review FAC Report
- Troubleshooting on Activity Expansion and New site on air such as RTWP, Traffic lost, Cross sector, HO Failure, Call drop, Load balance etc.

Engineer at Advanced info service Plc, Region of Central

November 2019 - August 2021

Radio Planning and Optimization Engineering

- RF Survey and Design site solution
- · Prepare new site Parameter
- Review Huawei Site Drawing and Tower load
- Review Huawei Cluster Tuning Report LTE and NR
- Analyst worse cell and customer complaint
- Analyst drive test log file and MDT(Huawei Smartcare) for improveNetwork quality UMTS/LTE/NR
- Follow up rollout progress
- Verify Design Report IBC (In building)
- Estimate budget and revenue for request new site
- · Support site event and festival
- Develop an automatic tool for check the accuracy of the information in the master plan (Among AIS plan, Huawei progress, Parameter in network)
- Support project tracking azimuth by IOT device
- Support project collect MML result of RRN by python Huawei iSStar

RF Engineer at Cellconsult Co.,Ltd

October 2019 — November 2019

Project: Swap ZTE to Nokia AIS, Northeast

• Optimize cluster PAC report UMTS LTE

RF Engineer at Elabram Systems Co., Ltd

November 2018 — June 2019

Project: NQG AIS-Nokia ,Northeast

- Optimize Coverage and quality of UMTS and LTE
- Check KPI (Accessibility, Retain ability, Mobility, Traffic, Utilization)
- Cooperate with Nokia team for solve interference in key city
- Summarize report benchmarking drive test both RSRP and SINR
- · Setup drive test tool on UE

Details

177/4 Phon Sub-district KhamMuang District, Kalasin Province, 46180, Thailand, 099-219-9586 Bu.narakorn@gmail.com

Date / Place of birth

25-01-1994

Kalasin

Nationality

Thailand

Driving license

63002488

Skills

Microsoft Office

Python

SQL

VBA

C,C#

HTML

Project:ZTE AIS LTE 2CA 1800, 2100 IN NORTH- EAST (PHASE 1)

- Present daily and weekly progress to ZTE and the internal management team.
- Plan and assigned work (Managing DTA, DTE, Rigger)
- Install software test tool and setup UE to initiate the project
- · Drive test by Nemo outdoor and WNG

September 2017 — November 2017

Project: Huawei AIS Turnkey Project North.

- Process and analyze DT log files using Actix Analyzer.
- Analysis the cell data each such as azimuth, tilt, Scrambling code, RSRP, RSRQ, PCI, CQI, SINR, Ec/No, propagation delay, handover and etc.
- Analysis KPI, drop call, setup failures, missing neighbors, low throughput and coverage issue.
- Prepare PA report 1st, 2nd, 3rd and 4thround, Defined problem area (PA) of cluster by Actix Analyzer.
- Propose solution and recommend change to fix it.
- Identifying reasons of poor network quality and suggesting changes in RNC parameters, Neighbors, antenna orientations and antenna physical tilts, etc.
- SSO Tuning and SSO Acceptance (LTE 2100 and 1800).

October 2016 — September 2017

Project:ZTE AIS 3G NORTHEAST

- Pre-Analysis and check log-files drop call, call failure, call attempt, UMTS coverage, such as RSCP, Ec/No, throughput both HSDPA and HSUPA, etc. on UMTS network.
- Perform analysis the log-file for check crossed sector, check the physical tilling, and identify coverage holes.
- Perform analysis the cell data of each such as azimuth, E-tilt, M-Tilt, scrambling code, RSCP, Pilot pollution, handover, etc.
- Defined and tuning each problem area (PA) of cluster to optimum point and proposed the solution.
- Prepared the DT KPI
- Perform Change Request at AIS and Update CR in every week.
- Prepare SSV report, 1st, 2nd, 3rd and 4thround of Coverage optimization report by Actix Analyzer and MapInfo Professional.
- Prepare HSDPA and HSUPA of HSXPA optimization report by Actix Analyzer and MapInfo Professional.

May 2016 — October 2016

Project:Huawei-DTAC 3G 4G in North-East & North (PAC)

- Perform analysis the cell data of each such as azimuth, tilt, scrambling code, RSCP, PSC
- Optimization (parameters changing, Antenna azimuth & Tile adjustment, CPICH in Huawei)

Education

2012 - 2016

- King Mongkut's University of Technology Thonburi Bachelor's Degree Faculty of Engineering (Electronic & Telecommunication) GPAX:3.04 2010 — 2012
 - Kalasinpittayasan school (Sci-Math) GPAX:3.71

Internships

Symphony Communication Public Company Limited

November 2015 — May 2016

- Learn Configure IP address with Network planning team (CCNA)
- Coding program for Check configuration of The planning team

Experience in using software and Courses Training

Analyst Tool

- Actix Analyzer
- NEMO Analyzer
- · TIBCO Spotfire
- ATOLL
- · WNG Analyzer

GIS Software

• Google Earth / Global Mapper / QGIS / MapInfo Professional

O&M Tool

• Huawei: U2020, PRS, Ran discovery, SON master, iSStar

• Nokia: NetAct , NePA

• Ericsson: ENM, AMOS, MobaXterm

• ZTE: EMS

Drive test Tool

• NEMO Outdoor / WNG (ZTE's software) / Azengos

Training

Python for Data Science and Machine Learning

Analyzing Data with Python

Python for Huawei iSStar

Huawei Technology for partner (3G/4G)

Robotic Process Automation by Uipath

Internet of Things Projects with Arduino IOT

5G Air Interface Training

5G Protocols and Signaling Analysis Training

5G Radio Network & Transmission Planning Training